# Christopher Allsman

Mobile Phone +1 (559) 288 2499

Email

callsman97@gmail.com

## **Summary of Qualifications**

Computer science graduate with 3 years of experience in undergraduate education. Knowledgable about curriculum development, pedagogy, and issues faced in running computer science courses. Experienced in working in team environments and able to contribute meaningfully, communicate clearly, and manage tasks independently.

#### Education

2015-2019 BA in Computer Science - The University of California, Berkeley

Graduated with High Distinction Outstanding Undergraduate Teaching and Leadership Award recipient

## Experience

Aug 2017 - University of California, Berkeley Aug 2019 Instructor - CS 61A (May 2019 - Aug 2019)

Head Teaching Assistant - Content (Aug 2018 - May 2019) Teaching Assistant (Aug 2017 - May 2018)

- Designed curriculum for a new online offering of the course with 200 students enrolled
- Addressed logistical and administrative issues such as exam proctoring, grading, and scheduling for 600 students
- Created processes for mentoring and supervising over 30 staff members and 70 academic interns
- Developed lab, project, homework, and discussion assignments used by 600-1700 students per semester

Jan 2018 - Computer Science Mentors

May 2019 Internal Vice President (Jan 2019 - May 2019) Course Coordinator (Jan 2018 - Jan 2019)

- Constructed curriculum and organized logistics for small-group tutoring, serving over 450 students
- Facilitated communication across courses to standardize teaching and administration of policies
- Provided tutors with training in teaching techniques and multicultural competency

### Skills

- Expertise in data analysis using Python and Excel
- Expertise with Git version control
- Experience with Java, C, C++, SQLite